hi welcome to the eev blog an
Electronics engineering video blog of
interest to anyone involved in
electronics design I'm your host Dave
Jones we're going to announce um and
launch our RX design contest tonight and
guys right now it's the official
launch it's one of the biggest and best
contest we've ever
done it's going to be Global we have uh
Europe and parts of Asia participate in
this
contest and what's interesting is for
the first time our alliance partners are
joining this and uh supporting and
sponsoring this concept so it's very
powerful having the support of these
Alliance partners and and what does this
partnership or sponsorship by these
great Alliance Partners means it means
that together Renaissance and these
Partners we have put up 110,000
in cash and FES for the winners that's
[Applause]
amazing you know recently at BSC Boston
one of our competitors uh announced a
contest and I think it was $15,000
$15,000 so uh you can compare it it's
it's amazing1 $110,000 in cash and
prizes and it's going to be distributed
over for month 30
opportunities of course the awards first
and foremost will be based on technical
merits
originality they have to be useful you
know like those beer mugs we had last
night with the LED lights going on got
to be
useful they have to be cost
effective and uh you know these days
documentation if you want to a video or
good stear documentation V be and most
of FKS we going to chose public interest
for voting so it's going to be online
it's going to be you know social media
so be uh public in as
well you will have or the content
contestants will have until March 4th
2011 to submit your
design and we will do the final judging
live at the upcoming and better
assistance conference in San Jose
which is they call it the spring ESC
[Music]
2011 now for us to enable you to submit
those original and useful designs we
have allocated
1,3 Renaissance development kits for the
rx6 so uh we're we're really going to
enable a lot of people to try to
participate in this contest for the
$110,000 in cash and prices now to talk
about this board we have a special guest
here Mor Wright most of you know him as
Dr mro and our Renaissance rules blog
page he's here to share with you uh the
importance of this Bo please welcome Mor
rice thank you my name is Mor right
although it's been uh Dr Michael have
answer to most of this week it's been
very gratifying for those of you been
asking if I was expect Dr mik the
classrooms and uh I appreciate you
reading the
blog I uh really excited about the
contest and exciting about the RX
architecture in general it's been a lot
of fun for the past 6 months getting a
chance to investigate the ARs
architecture and provide about it on a
regular basis and now um I'm excited
about the opportunity actually
participate in the judging and to
continue the the Dr Michael blog and
among other things cover the progression
of the contest
and I want to talk a little bit about
the board which you see on the screen I
think it's just a outstanding platform
for a contest U the the contestants will
probably for the most part get their
hands on the RX 62 in microl for the
very first time with the full complement
of communications or and peripherals
such as ethernet USB and can but the
platform is way more than that because
it has a host of other good stuff on the
board from third Pary is uh from Analog
Devices we have three n sensors U three
AIS
accelerometer um a digital thermometer a
microphone there's a fantastic Graphics
display you see there it's pretty small
but it's amazing how much you can put on
that Graphics display there's also a
flash device there's an Ethernet F from
Nashville semiconductor and great for
Sager so it's it's a platform that I
think will allow the tests to really
come up with compelling application for
and something I I really look forward to
judging I I'd also like to just mention
the demonstrations that come with the
board because I think those
demonstrations will both uh help the
design contest entrance don't start
their project and and probably will
inspire ideas uh for example there is a
motor control demonstration that comes
with the kit and that motor control
demonstration uses that circular area of
LEDs that you see to simulate the
different phases of a motor drive so I
look forward to seeing how creative all
you can be and to participate in the
judging and also to block about going
forward now I want to introduce another
engineer that's going to be involved in
the process as well you may have seen
him around here with his camera this
week you probably know him best for his
presence on the internet his e Block
Please welcome da Jo
[Music]
[Applause]
hi I'm D
J and my secret talents have been
unusual every week I educate and
entertain news like me on YouTube and
trust me that takes a lot of talent roll
the tape let's blow some
[Music]
up Cy what is that check out the input
circuitry a isn't that sex on a stick
why they prob went back to the cubicles
and just started bashing their head
against the desk it wins the E B
product of the week
award CRA look this is actually a real
fa flying here watch
this oh
je no go away I'm a professional design
engineer I don't need design advice it's
all over the shop it's messy I don't
like it it sucks
let's have some
[Music]
fun so silly horrible springing sound in
that like you just
the Fantastic new technology that can
make it work well I smell
one person one hobbyist one
hacker one maker can change the world
thank I believe a l on my own stuff
that's terrible I've never seen myself
on such a big screen I'm so used to
watching myself on YouTube on a tiny
little YouTube scen uh I don't have any
speech prepared today I'm off the cuff
um as I already introduce myself my name
is David Jones I'm the host of the
electronics engineering video blog uh if
you don't know the accent I am
Australian uh from Sydney uh I'm not New
Zealand or English so please don't get
it mied
up and uh I basically do a weekly
Electronics engineering show which
should be of interest to most electronic
Engineers out there if you like my style
that's pretty much a summary of um some
of the wacky stuff I get up to I do
product reviews uh product tear Downs
design tutorials and I like to rant
about bad product design basically if
something's crack I'll call it crap
that's something I enjoy doing um so if
you want to see the show it's um it's on
every week it's on eog.com so that's a
little plug for myself if I can get away
with that now Anis have asked me to be
uh involved in the RX design context
I've got one here and I'm super excited
really this is uh great design contest
I've been involved in a lot of uh design
contests over the years both entering
and watching and there's even I know
somebody in the audience who's won a
previous design uh contest and a lot of
them are pretty lame they even got U you
know they might be $5,000 total prize
money we're talking
$110,000 it's massive I've never seen a
des contest this big so excited from
that respect um from that aspect and
also um uh there are just so many prizes
involved really it's just unbelievable
if you don't win a prize in this I mean
you can always get something for a lead
flasher there's that many prizes
involved there's not just one major
prize so it's fantastic now I'm going to
be involved in this several ways uh the
first way is I will be a judge at ESC
along with B Mor who introduced me uh
along with several others here as well
and um our job is to I guess go by the
con
rules but um I do like stuff that's cool
so if you design something cool that it
doesn't quite meet the criteria it's
going to get up there so guys make some
cool stuff okay I'm sure you can with
this the amount of power on this RX Bo
is phenomenal the amount of the feature
set you get um all stuff buil in as
Glory went over it's just incredible so
um you can do anything you imagine with
it um now so I'll be a judge at ESC I
will also um have a regular video Vlog
it'll be both on the eev vog and on the
r rules site as the contest goes along
uh I'll be uh tearing down the board and
doing some uh probably some examples and
showing you how it works and uh giving
you ideas and things like that and I'll
uh thirdly I'll most likely be uh
talking um I'll most lik to be reviewing
some of the uh some of the entries so if
they're no good well you might get a bit
of a serve so make sure they're
interesting make sure they're creative
make sure they're cool and uh have some
fun with this RX design contest and uh
I'd like to thank everyone uh who's been
involved in this cuz it really is
fantastic so get to work guys get one of
these it's free can you believe it if
you haven't picked one up okay see one
of the Renaissance people I'm sure they
can hook you up with one it's a it's got
99 bucks written on the back there it is
99 us you don't have to buy it they're
going to give it away unbelievable so
the contest and I hope you do well
thanks thanks a lot
[Music]